Guide to the Vardis Fisher Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Vardis Fisher Papers
1870-1990
1917-1968
YCAL MSS 555
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
43.45
(74 boxes)
The Vardis Fisher papers document the personal and professional life of prolific Western novelist and author Vardis Fisher.
Fisher, Vardis, 1895-1968
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired through various gifts and purchases, 1958-1996.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Existence and Location of Copies
Portions of the collection also avaliable on microfilm. Consult Access Services for additional information.
Vardis Fisher (1895-1968)
Vardis Fisher was born March 31, 1895 in Annis, Idaho to Joseph Oliver and Temperance (Thornton) Fisher. He was educated at the University of Utah (A.B., 1920) and the University of Chicago (A.M., 1922 and Ph.D., 1925).
After graduating from the University of Chicago, Fisher taught for several years as an assistant professor of English at the University of Utah (1925-1928) and New York University (1928-1931) before returning to Idaho, where he served as director of the Federal Writers Project for the state of Idaho (1935-1939) and as an editor and contributor to various periodicals from the late 1930s until his death in 1968.
Fisher won a number of awards for his literary and non-fiction work, including the Harper Prize in 1939 for Children of God, the Wrangler Award for best Western historical novel in 1965 for Mountain Man, and the Spur Award in 1966 and 1969. Fisher's novel Mountain Man was made into a popular film ( Jeremiah Johnson ), starring Robert Redford, by Sydney Pollack in 1972.
Fisher married three times: to Leona McMurtrey, 1918; Margaret Trusler, 1928; and Opal Laurel Holmes, 1940.
Biographical information taken from "Vardis (Alvero) Fisher." Contemporary Authors Online. Detroit: Gale, 2003. Gale Biography In Context. Web. 7 Mar. 2012.
Scope and Contents
The Vardis Fisher papers document the personal and professional life of prolific Western novelist and author Vardis Fisher. The collection contains material relating to writing projects, personal and family correspondence, photographs, financial records, and personal papers. Writings include notes for large projects, such as the multi-volume Testament of Man, as well as drafts, proofs, printed versions, and other materials for numerous novels, non-fiction, and shorter works dating from the mid 1930s onward. There are drafts and other materials, for example, for his successfull early novel Children of God (1939) to his late Suicide or Murder? (1962), an analysis of the death of Meriwether Lewis. Personal correspondence includes incoming and outgoing letters with friends, writers, publishers, magazines, and others. Additional Fisher material includes financial records, clippings, and personal papers. There is also a fair amount of unsorted correspondence, Fisher family correspondence, Opal Fisher correspondence, and photographs.
Arrangement
Organized chronologically by acquisition into five groupings: I. 1958-1968 Acquisitions, 1936-1962. II. August 1992 Acquisition, 1905-1990. III. June 1993 Acquisition, 1870-1984. IV. December 1996 Acquisition, [circa 1930s-1980s]. V. December 1998 Acquisition, [circa 1940s-1960s].
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Fisher, Vardis, 1895-1968
- I. 1958-1968 Acquisitions, 1931-1967; 12.51' (30 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into two groupings: Writings and Correspondence.
  Scope and Contents
  Contains material relating to writing projects and correspondence. Writings include notes for large projects, such as the multi-volume Testament of Man, as well as drafts, proofs, and other materials for numerous novels, non-fiction, and shorter works dating from the mid 1930s onward. Correspondence consists of incoming and outgoing letters with friends, writers, publishers, magazines, and others, and includes unsorted material.
  Former call number: Za Fisher.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Acquired from various sources, 1958-1968.
  - Writings
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - "April: a Fable of Love", 1936; 2 (Box 1)
    - "The Best is Yet to Be" (Box 1)
    - "Charivari" (Box 1)
    - "Children of God", 1939; 3 (Box 1)
    - "Children of God", 1939; 3 (Box 2)
    - "City of Illusion", 1958; 3 (Box 2)
    - "City of Illusion", 1958; 3 (Box 3)
    - "Forgive Us Our Virtues", 2 (Box 3)
    - "A Goat for Azazel", 1959; 3 (Box 3)
    - "A Goat for Azazel" (Box 4)
    - "Hows Your Sense of Humor?" (Box 4)
    - "Idaho: A Guide", 1937 (Box 4)
    - "Idaho Folklore", 1938 November 2 (Box 4)
    - "The Island of the Innocent", 1958 August 20; 3 (Box 5)
    - "Jesus Came Again", 2 (Box 5)
    - "Martha's Vacation" (Box 5)
    - "The Mountain Man", 1962 October 21; 3 (Box 6)
    - "My Holy Satan"
      - Original draft, 1958 August 20; 3 (Box 6)
      - Original typescript (Box 6)
      - Original typescript (Box 7)
      - Galley proof (Box 7)
      - Page proof, 1959 (Box 7)
    - "Neither Overalls Nor Dinner Jacket" (Box 7)
    - "The Neurotic Nightingale" (Box 7)
    - "No Villain Need Be", [1935] (Box 7)
    - "No Villain Need Be", [1935] (Box 8)
    - "Orphans in Gethsemane" (Box 8)
    - "Passions Spin the Plot", 1937 September 8; 3 (Box 8)
    - "Peace Like a River"
      - Original draft, 1958 August 20; 2 (Box 9)
      - Original typescript, 1959; 2 (Box 9)
      - Galley proofs (Box 9)
      - Galley proofs (Box 10)
      - Page proofs (Box 10)
    - "Pemmican" (Box 10)
    - "A Reply to Dick Lake's Report on 'Forgive Us Our Virtues'" (Box 10)
    - "Suicide or Murder?"
      - Notes and drafts, 14 (Box 11)
      - Notes and drafts, 16 (Box 12)
    - "Tale of Valor"
      - Original manuscript, 1957 September 10; 2 (Box 13)
      - Publisher's copy, 3 (Box 13)
    - "Testament of Man"
      - Miscellaneous notes on 4x6 cards (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 4x6 cards (Box 15)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 3x5 cards (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 3x5 cards (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 3x5 cards (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 3x5 cards (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous notes on 3x5 cards (Box 20)
    - "To Idahoans" (Box 21)
    - "The Valley of Vision", 1958 August 20 (Box 21)
    - "We Are Betrayed" (Box 21)
  - Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - A-E to Vardis Fisher (Box 22)
    - Abelard Press (Box 22)
    - Almat Publishing Corporation (Box 22)
    - American Book Collector (Box 22)
    - Babb, James T. (Box 22)
    - Bloch, Hans (Box 22)
    - Boyd, Julian P. (Box 22)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 22)
    - Brown, James L. (Box 22)
    - Caxton Printers, 1931-1939; 3 (Box 22)
    - Caxton Printers, 1931-1939; 3 (Box 23)
    - Ciardi, John (Box 23)
    - Clark, Walter V. T. (Box 23)
    - Cowley, Malcolm (Box 23)
    - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (Box 23)
    - Derleth, August (Box 23)
    - Doubleday Co., 2 (Box 23)
    - Doubleday, Doran and Company (Box 23)
    - F-K to Vardis Fisher (Box 23)
    - Hans Fischer Literary Agency (Box 24)
    - Fisher, Vardis (outgoing)
      - A-H (Box 24)
      - Abelard Press, N.Y., 1949-1954 (Box 24)
      - Babb, James T., 3 (Box 24)
      - Bakeless, John, 2 (Box 24)
      - Caxton Printers (Box 24)
      - Curtis Brown, Ltd. (Box 24)
      - Doubleday Co. (Box 24)
      - Fisher, Margaret T., 2 (Box 24)
      - Ghiselin, Brewster (Box 24)
      - Gossett, James P. (Box 24)
      - Harper and Brothers (Box 24)
      - I-Z (Box 24)
      - Kohn, John S. Van E. (Box 24)
      - Johnson, Wendell, 1948-1956 (Box 24)
      - Larson, Kenneth (Box 24)
      - McGraw-Hill Book Co. (Box 24)
      - Merriam, H. G. (Box 24)
      - Nowell, Elizabeth, 1935-1954 (Box 24)
      - Nowell, Elizabeth, 1955-1958; 2 (Box 25)
      - Reiter, Isidore H., 1957-1967; 7 (Box 25)
      - Reiter, Isidore H., undated (Box 26)
      - Roseman, Herbert (Box 26)
      - Swisher, Perry (Box 26)
      - Vanguard Press, 1942-1957; 2 (Box 26)
      - Warren, Dale (Box 26)
      - Westlake, Neda M. (Box 26)
      - Unsorted correspondence (Box 26)
    - Flora, Joseph M. (Box 26)
    - Foote, Ellis, 3 (Box 26)
    - Geismar, Maxwell (Box 26)
    - Goodenough, Erwin (Box 26)
    - Gordon, Caroline (Box 26)
    - Goshe, Frederick (Box 26)
    - Hansen, Harry (Box 26)
    - Havighurst, Walter (Box 26)
    - Haydn, Hiram (Box 26)
    - Idaho Observer (Box 26)
    - Idaho Statesman (Box 26)
    - Jackson, Donald D. (Box 27)
    - Johnson, Daisy (Mrs. Frank) (Box 27)
    - L-M (Box 27)
    - Langworthy, Edward (Box 27)
    - Larson, Kenneth, 2 (Box 27)
    - Levine, Isaac Don (Box 27)
    - Lottinville, Savoie (Box 27)
    - Manfred, Frederick, 1956-1965; 2 (Box 27)
    - Marti-Ibanez, Felix, 2 (Box 27)
    - Milton, John R. (Box 27)
    - William Morrow Company, 2 (Box 27)
    - N-S (Box 28)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 28)
    - Nowell, Elizabeth
      - Vardis Fisher, 1935-1958; 4 (Box 28)
      - Publishers concerning Vardis Fisher, 1955-1956 (Box 29)
      - Allen, W. H. (Box 29)
      - Aswell, Edward C. (McGraw-Hill) (Box 29)
      - Doubleday Co. (Box 29)
      - William Heinemann, Ltd. (Box 29)
      - Pearn, Pollinger Higham, Ltd. (Box 29)
    - Pead, Richard J. (Box 29)
    - Pead, Richard J. and Margaret (Box 29)
    - Random House (Box 29)
    - Rascoe, Burton (Box 29)
    - Reiter, Isidore H., 3 (Box 29)
    - Sandoz, Mari (Box 29)
    - Smith, Paul Jordan (Box 29)
    - Swisher, Perry (Box 29)
    - T-Z (Box 29)
    - Van Doren, Mark (Box 29)
    - Vanguard Press (Box 29)
    - Wheelock, John Hall (Box 29)
    - Yale University (Box 29)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 18 (Box 30)
- II. August 1992 Acquisition, 1905-1990; 5.42' (13 boxes)
  Organized into four subgroupings: Fisher Family Correspondence, Writings, Other Writings, and Miscellaneous.
  Contains Fisher family correspondence, writings by and about Fisher, and personal papers.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 238.
  Purchased on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund and Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 1992.
  - Fisher Family Correspondence
    - Correspondence, 1905-1924; 10 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, 1925-1932; 11 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1940; 10 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1956; 8 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1962; 10 (Box 35)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1980s; 13 (Box 36)
    - Correspondence, undated; 8 (Box 37)
  - Writings
    - Writings by Vardis Fisher, 1933-1950; 6 (Box 38)
    - Magazine articles about Vardis Fisher, 1918-1990, undated; 6 (Box 39)
    - Newspaper articles about Vardis Fisher, 1925-1989, undated; 10 (Box 40)
  - Other Writings
    - Manuscript drafts, 3 (Box 41)
    - Novels - book covers, etc., 2 (Box 41)
    - Articles used for research (Box 41)
  - Miscellaneous
    - School memorabilia, 2 (Box 42)
    - Poetry (Box 42)
    - Genealogy (Box 42)
    - Biographical family information (Box 42)
    - Patriarchal blessings (Box 42)
    - Family memorabilia, 2 (Box 42)
    - Financial records (Box 42)
    - Unsorted correspondence, 4 (Box 42)
    - Notebooks (Box 43)
    - Receipts, 3 (Box 43)
    - Unsorted files, 2 (Box 43)
- III. June 1993 Acquisition, 1870-1984; 1.5' (3 boxes)
  Organized into four groupings: Correspondence, Writings, Printed Material, and Photographs.
  Contains a small amount of additional correspondence and writings, as well as photographs of Fisher and members of the Fisher family and audio recordings.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 286.
  Purchased from D'Archivists on the Sinclair Lewis and Donald Windham-Sandy Campbell Collection Endowment funds, 1993.
  - Correspondence
    - Fisher, Temperance Thornton, 1927-1961 (Box 44)
    - Murphy, Katy and Forrest, 1962-1966, undated (Box 44)
    - Mead, Irene, 1957-1966, undated (Box 44)
    - Nasman, Donna, 1963-1964, undated (Box 44)
    - Unidentified, 1961-1964, undated (Box 44)
  - Writings
    - "Bishop William Hainey Hickenlooper" and "Joseph Cylvenus Fisher" (Box 44)
    - Editorials, 1942-1965 (Box 44)
    - Writings of others
      - Bibliographies, 1961-1984, undated (Box 44)
      - Book reviews, 1939-1961 (Box 44)
      - Diary of Temperance Thornton Fisher, typescript, 1941-1942 (Box 44)
      - News articles, 1939-1970 (Box 44)
  - Printed Material
    - Eastern Idaho Farmer, 1966-1968 (Box 44)
  - Photographs
    - Vardis Fisher alone, 1914-1921, undated (Box 44)
    - Vardis Fisher with others, 1915-1940, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher - general, 1934, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Irene and Vivian, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Joseph Cylvenus, 1870, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Leona McMurtrey, 1917-1921, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Margaret Trusler and Robert, 1923-1948, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Temperance Thornton and Joseph Oliver, 1894-1959, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Opal, undated (Box 44)
    - Fisher, Wayne and Grant, 1919-1929, undated (Box 44)
    - McMurtrey, 1922, undated (Box 44)
    - Others, 1917-1924, undated (Box 44)
    - Places: Fisher's homes, 1916-1954, undated (Box 44)
    - Places: other, 1910-1917, undated (Box 44)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 44)
  - Photographs (Box 45 Oversize)
  - Rolled photographs (Box 46)
  - Audio recordings (reel-to-reel), 6
    3-inch audiotape reels (6)
    - From Vardis Fisher to Grant Fisher, 1965 November 26; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504320)
      Single-track tape
    - family gossip, Wayne's letter, 1967 June 29; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504338)
      From Opal and Vardis to Grant and Billie; Dad talks about Ro[eb] Rights; 4-track
    - Tape of Dad and Opal, 1966 [?] February 22; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504346)
      Opal talking to Steve, also to Sherry; dad talking about money; who is best for Opal; dad talking about going blind; bad bladder. Vardis is 70 on this tape. From V. Fisher to Grant Fisher.
    - From Vardis Fisher to Grant Fisher/March of 70th year for Vardis, 1992 July 16; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504353)
    - Dad with Lloyd Jensen, 1992 July 15; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504361)
      This is a four-track tape. A note with the audiotape says Opal put it on a cassette.
    - Tape from Vardis Fisher to son Grant; Opal on part, 1992 July 14; 1 (Box 46, Item barcode 39002104504379)
- IV. December 1996 Acquisition, [circa 1930s-1980s]; 23.60' (27 boxes)
  Contains unsorted Vardis Fisher papers, including correspondence, writings, financial records, clippings, audiovisual material, and personal papers, as well as Opal Fisher correspondence and material about or relating to Fisher, such as shooting scripts and other material relating to the film Jeremiah Johnson, made after Fisher's death in 1972.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 509
  Gift of Grant R. and T. Robert Fisher, 1996.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 64 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile material.
  - Correspondence, clippings, and other papers, 21 (Box 47)
    Includes correspondence from publishers McGraw-Hill and Harper & Brothers
  - Correspondence and financial papers, 15 (Box 48)
    Includes correspondence from publisher Alan Swallow, Opal Fisher correspondence, financial statements, and documents relating to the Vardis Fisher Memorial Fund
  - Correspondence, writings, and clippings, 12 (Box 49)
    Includes correspondence about Vardis Fisher, scripts for "Jeremiah Johnson", and a collection of western essays
  - Writings and galley proofs, 12 (Box 50)
    Includes drafts of Fisher's manuscripts "Idaho Folklore", "Original Idaho Source Material", and "The Redwood", as well as galley proofs for "Orphans of Gethsemane"
  - Writings, financial papers, and clippings, 11 (Box 51)
    Includes essays by Vardis Fisher about the "Testament of Man" series and other works, invoices from publishers, a published interview of Vardis Fisher, and newspaper clippings
  - Newspaper clippings, 4 (Box 52)
  - Rolled material (Box 53)
    Includes graduation certificates and a map of "Shakespeare's London"
  - Correspondence and writings, 9 (Box 54)
    Includes Vardis and Opal Fisher correspondence to publishers and writings, including the essay "Western Writers and the Eastern Establishment"
  - Writings, scripts, and photographs, 12 (Box 55)
    Includes "Fact or Fiction: The Blend of History and Legend", a shooting script of "Jeremiah Johnson," and promotional photographs for the film
  - Correspondence, writings, and royalty statements, 41 (Box 56)
    Includes correspondence relating to Fisher's work, personal correspondence, drafts of Fisher's essay "The World's Greatest Physical Wonderland," and royalty statements
  - Correspondence, clippings, and notecards, 10 (Box 57)
    Includes correspondence from Don and Thelma Lewis, newspaper clippings of articles by and about Vardis Fisher, and notecards Fisher used for his writings
  - Correspondence and clippings, 18 (Box 58)
    Includes Opal Fisher correspondence concerning Vardis Fisher's death, financial matters, submissions to publishers, and clippings relating to the film "Jeremiah Johnson"
  - Correspondence and photographs, 17 (Box 59)
    Includes Vardis Fisher correspondence, Opal Fisher correspondence concerning the Vardis Fisher memorial, photographs, and miscellaneous files
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous files, 10 (Box 60)
    Includes Opal Fisher correspondence to publishers, miscellaneous drafts, and financial records
  - Newspaper clippings, 2 (Box 61)
    Includes drawing of "Primitive Idaho"
  - Correspondence, clippings, and publications, 13 (Box 62)
    Includes Opal Fisher correspondence to publishers and literary agencies, clippings of articles by Vardis Fisher, and copies of literary publications
  - Correspondence and photographs, 17 (Box 63)
    Includes Opal Fisher correspondence pertaining to the Vardis Fisher Memorial Fund and photographs of the Fisher family
  - Audiovisual material and photographic film negatives
    Includes 7-inch audio reels (15), 3-inch audio reels (16), cassette tapes (5), photographic film negatives, and one photograph
    - Wyler, Delbert. Western American Writers/Popular Westerns, 1974; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104503975)
      Time: 39 min.
    - Westbrook, Max. Western American Writers/The Works of Walter Van Tilburg Clark, 1974; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104503983)
      Time: 28 min.
    - Manfred, Frederick. Western American Writers/Writing in the West, 1974; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104503991)
      Time: 22 min.
    - Etulain, Richard. Western American Writers/The Mountain Man in Literature, 1974; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504007)
      Time: 44 min.
    - "The Scarlet Letter" voiced by Ermance Rejebian, 1983
      This appears to be a commerical audiocassette published by the Literary Digest.
    - Murphy, Forrest, and Katy, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504015)
      A note found with the audiotape reel reads: a fight on A channel and B. drunk.
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504023)
    - Untitled, undated; 1; The tape is blank. It has not been digitized. (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504031)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504049)
      The tape contains symphony music.
    - Music, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504056)
      A list of contents are included with the audiotape reel. They are included below.
      Anon: 2 Versions of Hole in the Wall; Schulze/Telemann Society (3:05)
      Vivaldi: L'Estro #11 in D min; Ord/Pro Arte Orch (9:56)
      Mendelssohn: A Midsummer Night's Dream Ovt; Szell/C'gebouw Orch (11:32)
      Saint-Saens: Omphale's Spinning Wheel; Mitropoulos/NY Phil (7:12)
      Brahms: Hungar Dance #6 in D flat; Kubelik/Royal Phil (2:41)
      Mozart: Divertimento in B flat; Stepp/Munich Chamber Orchestra (12:50)
      Glinka: A Night in Madrid; Perlea/Bamberg (9:02)
      Goldmark: Conc in A min; Swoboda/Vienna (34:27)
      Debussy: Danses Sacree et Profane; van Beinum/Amsterdam Music Society (9:34)
      Cosi Fan Tutti, Aria, SOP, Act I
      Raymond Ovt - Thomas - Orch
      Barber of Baghdad - Act II Finale
      Michaud - Le Boeufsur le Toit - Orch (16:27)
      Bliss - Dance of Summer; Royal Op (2:56)
      Gould - Spirituals for Orch. Hague Sym (16:12)
      Bach - Suite #1C, oboes and casals; Puerto Rico Sym. (21:00)
      Neri: Sonata a Quattro in G; Quartetto Ital (9:24)
      Mozart: Landler; Landowska, h'chord (3:06)
      Beethoven: Sonata #29 in B flat; Schnabel, piano (41)
      Hammer klavier (1932)
    - Music Vardis?, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504064)
    - Music Vardis, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504072)
    - Music taped by Dale Gates, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504080)
      A list of four tracks are included with this audiotape reel.
      Tracks
      1. Music of the Sea
      2. Grieg. Piano Concerto
      3. Delius - North Country Sketches; Misc. Music
      4. A Strauss-Suite in B-Flat for Woodwinds, 50 Guitars Go South of the Border
    - Bob Fisher singing, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504098)
      Side 2A
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504106)
    - Ballroom Dances/Gay, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504114)
      A note found with the audiotape reel reads: Guy Lombardo, etc. music. A list of contents are also listed.
      I-A Ballroom Dances/2-A Gay
      Weber, Inv to dance Poliakin
      Strauss Jr, Vienna Life
      Aliber
      Delibes, Pizz Polka Schercher
      Delibes, Naila Waltz
      Delibes, Lente Waltz
      Strauss, Sylphen-Polka Long.
      Fiedler, Medley Boston Pops
      Tschai, Sleeping Beauty Waltz
      Ziehrer, In the Friendly Night
      Herbert, It Happened in Nord Land
      Marchetti, Fascination
      Hash of Blue Voices Roses, Tales Emperor waltzes
      Fiedler Medley
      Smetena, Bartered Bride Polka
      Saint-S, The Swan
      R-K, Dance of the Buffoons
      Hash of Waldteufel Skater's & Estud; Rosas Over the Waves
      Welk in various
      Offenbach Can-Can
      Copland, Hoedown fr Rodeo
      R-K, Fandango fr Spanish Caprice
      Lumbye, Champagne Gallop
      Waldteufel, Tout Paris
      Waldteufel, Par ci par la
      Thurban, Watermelon Fete
      Herbert fr Serenade
      Welk, Champagne Medley
      Rossini, Magpie Overture
      Fun in Tyrol: dancers and band of Kitzbuehel
      Harmonicats various
      Los Gittanillos de Cadiz in flamenco
      Opera drinking songs; Verdi, Strauss, Verdi, Flotow, Mozart, Donisetti, Mozart, Arriete
      Randolph singers catch songs
      Mozart, Rondo Turca
      Gioconda, Final du Ballet
      Yodelers fr Austria Rudi & Inge Meixner (the long instrumental piece that endures it is)
      Offenback, Parisian gayety to conc 1222
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504122)
      A variety of symphony music is heard on the tape.
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504171)
    - Grant, Spelling, etc., undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504130)
      A note on the audiotape reel box reads: This is only a two-track tape. But, I used two mikes so you will have to listen to both of your speakers. Grant. A list of possible contents is also noted. It reads: 1-A: Grant and Mel, Billie, Sharon, Grant; 2-A: Grant, Spelling, etc.
    - Vardis Fisher - 4 programs, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504148)
      Recorded at 1 7/8 inches per second; University of South Dakota
    - From G. Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504155)
    - From Gates to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504163)
    - From Grant Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504189)
    - From Grant Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504197)
    - From Dale Gates to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504205)